frontlinedefenders.org 2011-11-05

# Front Line Privacy Policy | Front Line

Front Line: The International Foundation for the Protection of Human Rights Defenders (Ireland charity number CHY14029) and Front Line (UK) Foundation (UK charity registration 1119643) (which are together referred to as ‘Front Line’ in this policy) are committed to protecting the privacy of their supporters. Front Line honours each of the individual and organizational supporters who have contributed to its programme of protection for Human Rights Defenders at Risk.

Front Line endeavours to protect all supporter information through compliance with the Irish Data Protection Act 1988, the Irish Electronic Communications Regulations 2003, the UK Data Protection Act 1998 and the UK Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003.

The personal information of all Front Line supporters who submit personal and sensitive information to the organization, is protected by a secure online and offline donation system.

Front Line may disclose your personal information to any member of Front Line’s group, which means its subsidiaries, including trading subsidiaries, for the purposes of carrying on its charitable activities, providing you with information and carrying out fundraising.

We use information held about you in the following ways:

  * To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer. 

  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes.

All such personal information about supporters is stored on the organization’s secure computerised database. Unless requested otherwise by the supporter, Front Line may communicate with its supporters by mail, email or telephone. 

Should any supporter wish to receive a copy of their personal information retained by Front Line, the organization will facilitate such requests upon full confirmation of the identity of the person inquiring. Front Line will respond within 40 calendar days.

Front Line may also collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about the browsing actions and patterns of the people who use our website, and does not identify any individual.

For the same reason, Front Line may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help Front Line to improve the site.

They enable Front Line :

To estimate audience size and usage pattern.

To store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise our site according to your individual interests.

To speed up your searches.

To recognise you when you return to the site.

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, Front Line’s system will issue cookies when you log on to our site.

All Front Line supporters have the right to have their personal data corrected, if inaccurate, or erased from our records. Front Line will respond within 40 calendar days.

Enquiries should be directed to the Data Officer in writing via email (Dataofficer@frontlinedefenders.org) or by post to 81 Main St, Blackrock, Co. Dublin.

## Personal information

Names, addresses, telephone numbers and email addresses are protected by Front Line on a secure computerised system which is designed to ensure that any risk of loss, misuse, unauthorised access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of personal donor information is kept to an absolute minimum.

Unfortunately, however, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, Front Line cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk.

## Sensitive information

All donations, including credit card numbers and account numbers received online are protected by a secure server software operated by a third party supplier called Paypal. This software encrypts financial information provided online and prevents any outside source from reading personal and sensitive donor information at any point during the donation process. Should you require any further information about this service please visit the supplier’s website at www.paypal.com.

Front Line does not retain credit card details once a transaction has been finalized unless the organization obtains consent from the donor to retain such details for monthly donation support.

Front Line’s site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

If you have any queries or questions about privacy and/or security of your personal data please contact Front Line at info@frontlinedefenders.org.

This policy is subject to change. Any such changes to Front Line’s privacy policy will be posted on this page without prior notification.
